# RADOSLAV BUKOV

Software Engineer



<u>radoslaw.bukow@gmail.com</u>







Experienced and highly trained engineer with 9+ years of proven experience in the field of Automation in Automotive industry. Strong understanding of Computer systems, PLC programming, Automatisation and Control systems, Mechatronics and etc. Proven capability to work independently or as a part of a team. Excellent leadership and communication skills. High interest and commitment to professional development and learning opportunities Last couple of years with strong interest and dedication in Web Development, Backend with Python and Django, and Frontend with JavaScript, HTML & CSS. You can find some of my projects in my GitHub account.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCES**



#### Head of Automatisation Department and Electrical Maintenance

Hronovsky I Jan 2020 - Present

Main Head role responsibilities:

- o Managing, scheduling, coaching and supporting the development of team members.
- o Developing training materials, provide and organise any training that team members need.
- o Manage the flow of day-to-day operations, coordinate team tasks, execution of an operative schedule.
- Create an environment oriented to trust, open communication, creative thinking, and cohesive team effort
- Familiarize the team with the customer needs, specifications, design targets, the development process, design standards, techniques and tools to support task
- o Coordinates meetings with the management to discuss project impediments, needed resources or issues/delays in completing the task.
- Developing plans to implement improvements with new automation technologies to increase efficiency and productivity levels within the company.

Main PLC Programmer responsibilities

- o Develop, update, maintain and implement improvements in the PLC software.
- o Installation, setup and develop specialized automated devices such as PLC, Visual systems, Industrial robots, Electronic sensors and others.
- o Creating a complete concept for development, programming, implementation and design change of automated equipment.

## Head of Automatisation Department and Electrical Maintenance

Kostal | Jan 2016 - Dec 2019

Smolyan,Bulgaria

Main Head role responsibilities:

- o Managing, scheduling, coaching and supporting the development of team members.
- o Developing training materials, provide and organise any training that team members need. Manage the flow of day-to-day operations, coordinate team tasks, execution of an operative schedule.
- Create an environment oriented to trust, open communication, creative thinking, and cohesive team effort.
- Familiarize the team with the customer needs, specifications, design targets, the development process, design standards, techniques and tools to support task performance
- o Coordinates meetings with the management to discuss project impediments, needed resources or issues/delays in completing the task.
- o Developing plans to implement improvements with new automation technologies to increase efficiency and productivity levels within the company.

Main PLC Programmer responsibilities:

- o Develop, update, maintain and implement improvements in the PLC software.
- o Installation, setup and develop specialized automated devices such as PLC, Visual systems, Industrial robots, Electronic sensors and others.
- o Creating a complete concept for development, programming, implementation and design change of automated equipment.

# Automation Engineer

Kostal | Aug 2014 - Dec 2016

Main PLC Programmer responsibilities

- o Update, maintain and implement improvements in the PLC software.
- o Installation, setup and develop specialized automated devices such as PLC, Visual systems, Industrial robots, Electronic sensors and others.
- o Creating a complete concept for development, programming, implementation and design change of automated equipment.
- Makes technical changes to the automated devices, correct defects of automated equipment and perform set tasks.
- Responsible for the overall maintenance of all automated systems in production (PLC, Vision systems, Robots and etc.).
- ° Working with colleagues from other departments in relation to the improvement of automation systems

## **EDUCATION**



Sofia, Bulgaria | Nov 21 - April 23

Python Web Developer

Python Web Developer course modules:

- Python Fundamentals
- o Python Advanced
- o Python OOP
- o Python Web Basics
- o Python Web Frameworks Django
- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript Front-end

#### SKILLS

#### Technical

PLC Controllers

Python/OOP/APIs

Diango/Weh/HTTP

lavaScript/DOM/Rest

HTML&CSS

SQL/PostgreSQL

Git/GitHub

Object-oriented design

Industrial Automatisation

Industrial Robots

Computer Vision

Lead and deliver complex software systems

### Professional

Effective communication

Team player

Mentoring skills

Leadership

Time management

Strong problem solver

# LANGUAGES

Bulgarian (Native) English (Professional)

### DRIVING LICENSE

B. B1

A, A1, A2, AM

# INTERESTS

Programming

Electronic Devices

Football

Gaming

Cinema & Movies Travelling

Master's Degree, Automation, Information and Control Systems

#### Activities and societies:

- o Adaptive control
- o Automated Manufacturing Systems
- Robotics
- o Fuzzy and Neuron Control
- o System Analysis
- o Management of Industrial Manipulators

Diplom thesis: Integration of automatic visual solder joint inspection in automotive components assembly system.



## Brno University of Technology

Brno, Czech Republic | Jan 14 - Apr 14

Master's Degree, Mechatronics, Robotics, and Automation Engineering

#### Activities and societies:

- o Control Theory
- o Digital Signal Processing
- o Robust and Algebraic control



#### Technical University of Sofia

Sofia, Bulgaria | Sep 09 - Jun 13

Bachelor's Degree, Automation, Information and Control Systems

#### Activities and societies:

- Microprocessors
- o Computer Simulation
- o Computer Control Systems
- Computer-integrated manufacturing systems
- o Automation of processes
- Automation of Manufacturing
- o Analysis and Recognition of pattern and scenes
- o Artificial Intelligence
- Logic Control

Diploma thesis: Synthesis of quadrotor position control system.

#### COURSES AND CERTIFICATES

#### Certificates

o Lean Six Sigma - Green Belt

o Leadership and comunnication skills

o Time management

- o C# Programming Basics
- o Python Programming Basics
- o Python Fundamentals
- o Python Advanced
- Python OOP
- Python Web Basics
- o Python Web Frameworks Django o Python HTML & CSS
- o Python JavaScript Front-end
- o Tightening Technique & CVIx2 controller settings, CVIPC
- o Staubli: Maintenance TS, TX/SC8C Level 1
- o Mitsubishi Robot Advanced Training
- o Fundamentals of Pneumatic and Electro Pneumatic
- o Cognex Corporation: Checker Vision Sensors
- IPC-7711/IPC-7721 Rework and Repair of Electronic Assemblies
- o Total Productive Maintenance
- o Root Cause Analysis

#### Courses

- o Beckhoff TwinCat 2
- o Beckhoff TwinCat 3 o Apollo Seiko, Janome
- o SICK 3D Visual System (IVC 3D)
- o Festo Servo motors
- o Inspector I40 Vision Sensor
- o 8D Reports
- o 5 Why

Lean.bg | Sofia, Bulgaria Academica Responsa | Sofia, Bulgaria SoftUni | Sofia, Bulgaria Desoutter | Bratislava, Slovakia Staubli | Pardubice, Czech Republik Mitsubishi | Plovdiv, Bulgaria Festo | Sofia, Bulgaria Mitsubishi | Plovdiv, Bulgaria IPC | Smolyan, Bulgaria Lean.bg | Sofia, Bulgaria Alfa Quality | Smolyan, Bulgaria

SC&C Partner | Brno, Czech Republik

Kastiva | Sofia, Bulgaria Apollo Seiko | Eindhoven, Netherlands Sick , inc.| Sofia, Bulgaria Festo | Sofia, Bulgaria Sick, inc. | Sofia, Bulgaria Kostal I Smolvan, Bulgaria Kostal | Smolyan, Bulgaria

in linkedin.com/in/radoslav-bukov-b0a62183/ github.com/RadoslavBukov

